there is a very good chance that you are
leaving most of the potential of your AI
coding assistant on the table. So right
now I want to get super practical with
you and show you some of the best
techniques that all the top agentic
engineers use for AI coding the people
that have a real system in place for
working with their coding agent like
claude code hero or cursor. And so I am
going to assume here that you have at
least a basic understanding of how to
use coding agents because now I want to
get specific into the really powerful
unlocks for you. And I'm going to be
very concise in my explanations here.
I'm not going to waste any of your time.
And the best part is all of this, it
doesn't require any new tools. It really
is just a better way of working. All
right, so let's get started. At the top
of the list here, we have PRD first
development. So PRD is short for product
requirement document and that can mean a
lot of different things but in this
context it is a markdown document a
single place to define the entire scope
of work for your project. And so for
green field development when you're
starting from scratch this generally
contains everything that you have to
build to complete your proof of concept
or your MVP. And the beauty of this is
this single document becomes the north
star for your coding agent. everything
that you have to build. And so from the
PRD, you get all of the individual
features that you're going to build out
with your coding agent. It is important
to not have your coding agent do too
much at once or it's going to completely
fall on its face. So you use the PRD as
a way to split your project into more
granular features like implementing the
API, implementing the user interface,
building the authentication in you split
it up like that. And then for brownfield
development, if you are working on an
existing codebase instead of creating
your initial scope of work, it's more
documenting what you already have in
your project and then what you want to
build next. But either way, you're
creating the north star for your
project. A lot of people miss this. They
dive right into building that first
feature, but then they don't really have
any connection between the different
iterations that they're doing with their
coding agent. And in order to
demonstrate all of the techniques that I
cover in this video, I have this GitHub
repository which I'll link to in the
description. I have a very basic demo
project built out in this repo as well
as all of the commands that I cover
here. And so all of my workflows that I
use day-to-day for AI coding. I have
this all laid out for you. These are the
core slash commands that I use every
day. And one of these commands is
related to what we were just talking
about. I have a full workflow built out
for you to help you create your PRDS. So
now going over to the repository
locally, I have all of the commands in
thecloud/comands
folder for you. And by the way, you can
use these commands for any AI coding
assistant, not just cloud code. They're
really just prompts that define these
workflows. And so I have the create PRD
command right here. And so the whole
point of this is you have a conversation
with an AI coding assistant about what
you want to build, right? Like I want to
build XYZ. help me plan it out. And once
you get to the point where you're on the
same page with the coding agent for what
you want to create in your conversation,
you just run slashcreate PRD and it'll
output to a document that you specify
here the entire scope of work. And so
for this simple habit tracker
application, this is my PRD. And all of
these sections are a part of the
template defined in the command. So
target users, your mission, what is in
scope, what is out of scope. You also
have the whole architecture laid out
here. This is now your northstar. So for
all of the feature development that you
do after this point, you're now going to
be referencing the PRD to figure out
what to build with the help of your
coding agent. So another command that I
always use in my AI development
workflows is a prime command. I run this
at the start of any new conversation to
load all of the necessary context in
from the project. And the PRD is one of
the core files that I always make sure
my agent reads because then after it
primes itself on the codebase, I can
just simply ask based on the PRD, what
should we build next? And this question,
I ask this every single day because I'm
showing you the workflow that I use no
matter what I'm building and it doesn't
matter what codebase I'm working on. All
right, so the next big concept to wrap
your head around is the idea of a
modular rules architecture. Cuz here's
the thing, most people make their global
rules way too long. Remember, these are
the constraints and conventions that are
loaded into the context for your coding
engine at the start of every single
conversation. So if it's not
lightweight, you're going to overwhelm
the LLM with the number of rules that
you have for it. And so your agents.md
or your claw.md, whatever your global
rule file is, you want to keep this
actually really short and focused on the
rules that apply no matter what you're
working on. things like the commands to
run, your testing strategy, your logging
strategy, that kind of thing. But when
you're working on just the front end,
maybe you're focusing on rules for your
components, or you're working on
deployments, you're working on building
out the API for your application, you
want to actually take these different
rules for different task types, split
them out into different markdown
documents, and have your primary global
rules reference these. So you're only
loading these into the context of your
LLM when you're working on something
that really applies to the rules that
you have laid out here. All right. So
going back to our handydandy habit
tracker application, I want to show you
an example of what these rules can look
like. And so I'm using cloud code. So
claw.md is my global rule file. And I'm
keeping this very lightweight. You can
see that I don't even have 200 lines in
my rules file here. But there's a lot
more context that I have in
mycloud/reference
folder. So, I'll show you this in just a
second, but what I have here is the
things that I care about no matter what
I'm working on. My tech stack. I want my
coding agent to know the project
structure so it can navigate it better.
What commands we have to run the front
end and backend, for example, MCP
servers, code conventions, my logging
standards. Remember, these are the
things that like literally no matter
what kind of feature I'm working on, I
want the LLM to know this information.
But here's the key thing. Right here, I
have a reference section. This is where
I refer to the task type specific
context that I want to load only for
certain types of features. And so
because these paths are loaded into our
global rules, the coding agent is going
to understand like, okay, when I'm
working on building API endpoints, that
is when I should read this file. And so
I have these all just living in my
codebase in this reference folder. And
so there's a lot more context here. Like
this document alone is almost a thousand
lines long. And it's the same for a lot
of these because this is where we get
very specific with our instructions. And
we're allowed to make this longer
because we're only going to read this
when we're actually working on our API.
And so having this reference section in
your global rules is a very powerful way
to keep your rules concise while still
having all the context that you need.
The goal is to protect the context
window of your coding agent. That is
something that a lot of people severely
underestimate the importance of. And you
can also reference these documents in
your commands as well. Like maybe you've
built up a workflow to build API
endpoints. So you don't actually have to
reference it here. You just have the
path given in one of the commands that
you have. So whatever it takes to make
sure that you have access to all the
context you need, but not all up front.
So the next technique that I have for
you is probably the most obvious out of
all of them. But it is so important that
I need to make sure this is always on
the forefront of your mind. You should
be commandifying everything, if that
really is a word. Basically, anytime you
send in a prompt to your coding agent
more than twice, that should scream to
you that it's an opportunity to turn it
into a command or a reusable workflow.
These are just markdown documents that
we load in as context to define a
process for our coding agent. And so
when you make a commit to git, when
you're doing a code review, when you are
loading context in from your codebase,
pretty much anything that you can
possibly do as a part of your
development workflow can be turned into
a command because it'll save you
thousands of keystrokes as you use it
more and more and more. And you can
share these workflows with other people
like I'm literally doing for you right
now. And going back to the habit tracker
repository, like I said earlier, I have
all of my core commands that I use on a
day-to-day basis documented here and
included in the repository. So you can
feel free to take all of these for
yourself and customize them to your own
use cases. So pretty much everything
that I found myself prompting more than
twice, I've packaged up into a workflow
here that you can feel free to use. So
making git commits, creating the PRD
like we saw earlier, everything in my
core feature development cycle like
executing, planning, priming, all of my
validation commands, even the ones for
system evolution that we'll talk about
in a little bit. I've got it all for you
here. And just to show you really
quickly everything that I cover in the
course, this is the complete system that
we build together for both green field
and brownfield development. I go over
how I build features in cycles, system
evolution to make our AI coding agent
more powerful over time. I cover it all
here. It is very, very comprehensive.
All right, the next technique that I
have for you is also related to context
management. If you couldn't tell
already, that is a very critical
component to working with coding agents.
And so, here we have the context reset.
And what I mean by this is in between
your planning and your execution where
you write the code, you should always
restart the conversation window with
your coding agent. And the only reason
you're able to do that is because you
always end your planning session by
outputting a document, typically a
markdown doc. And this document has all
of the context that you need to go into
the execution. So we're not going to do
any priming. We're not going to tell the
coding agent what we want to build when
we go into building our solution. That
next feature, we just feed it this
document. That is it. And the reason we
want to do this is because we want to
keep our context as light as possible
when we get into the actual coding to
leave as much room for the agent to
reason about what it's doing, do all the
self- validation, all that good stuff.
So, I'll show you right now what this
looks like using commands that I have
for you in the repository. So we always
start our planning with the prime
command. So we understand what's in our
codebase and then we have a conversation
with our coding agent to figure out what
we want to build next. Again using our
PRD based on our PRD what's the next
feature that makes sense. And so I
didn't go through this just the for the
sake of demonstration here. I went right
into the next command where we create
our structured plan. This is the
markdown document that we're going to
output that we use as context going into
execution. And so right here I will
literally do /cle. So completely wiping
the context window or you can just
restart your coding agent. And then I
call the execute command and the
parameter for this command is that plan
that I want it to read. That is all of
the context that it needs. And so I'll
show you that really quickly. Like for
this simple demo for the habit tracker,
we are improving the visuals for the
calendar. And so this outlines the
feature description, user story,
everything at a high level. All the
context to reference the individual
components we have to build out a task
by task breakdown. Like this is very
comprehensive because we're not loading
in any other context into our agent when
we execute the plan right here. Now,
believe it or not, I have actually saved
the most important technique for last
because now we are getting into system
evolution. And this is the most powerful
way to use coding agents when you treat
every bug as an opportunity to make your
coding agent stronger. And so instead of
just encountering a bug and fixing it
manually and moving on, we actually look
into the system for a coding agent, what
should we fix to make it so that this
issue doesn't happen again. This is
especially powerful when you see
patterns develop of an issue that your
coding agent keeps hallucinating time
and time again. And so typically when
you think about what you can fix in your
system, it's either your global rules,
any other kind of reference context like
we covered earlier, or your commands aka
workflows. There's going to be an
opportunity to address something here
because when the coding agent messes up
on something, it's probably a rule that
it doesn't understand that you want to
specify or it's a part of your process
for validation, for example, that could
be better. And so just for a couple of
examples that I have here, if the coding
agent uses the wrong import style, then
you add a new rule, right? Like you just
have a simple oneliner to explain what
that looks like. And a lot of times it
can just be a oneliner. AI forgets to
run tests. Well, you just update the
template for your structured plan. What
is fed into execution to include new
sections for testing. If the coding
agent doesn't understand the
authentication flow, well, that's when
you can create a new reference document.
and you would update your global rules
when working on authentication, you
should reference this doc just like we
showed up here. So, in the end, there
are a million different ways that we can
get into the system improvement mode
with our coding agent, but typically
you're going to do it right after you
finished building a feature and you
validated things yourself. you notice a
couple of things that are incorrect with
how the application works or something
wrong in the code and you just go in,
you say, "Hey Claude, I noticed that XYZ
is not working in the application and so
I had to make this fix." And so what I
want you to do is go into the rules,
read all of the commands that we used
here, and I want you to figure out what
we could improve in the process or the
rules so this issue doesn't happen
again. Now, this is a bit of an
oversimplification. And you can see I
used the speechto text tool to input
that here. But you get the general idea.
You have it do more of a self-reflection
thinking about how the execution
compared to the plan. How did it compare
to our rules and the process we laid
out? What are the discrepancies there?
Things that we can address so these bugs
don't come up again. And so I am very
loosely defining the strategy here
because if anything, this is just more
of a mindset that I want you to adopt.
Don't just fix the bug. fix the system
that allowed the bug. And that will take
you so far because your coding agent
just gets more powerful and more
reliable over time. So there you go.
Those are all of my favorite techniques
used by all of the top agentic
engineers. And like I said earlier, in
the description, I will link to the repo
with all the commands, the Dynamis
Agentic coding course, and this diagram
if you want to download it for yourself.
And so if you appreciated this video and
you're looking forward to more things on
Agentic Engineering, I would really
appreciate a like and a subscribe. And
with that, I will see you in the next